<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SRE Treats</title><link>https://sretreats.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on SRE Treats</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sretreats.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux Administration Essentials</title><link>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/linux-administration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/linux-administration/</guid><description>User/Group/Permission Management in Linux Users in Linux has an associated user ID called UID. A group is a collection of one or more users. A group makes it easier to share permissions among a group of users. Each group has a group ID called GID associated with it. Users can get sudo access if added to a sudo group in /etc/sudoers Below files are of importance here
1. /etc/passwd Stores the user name, the uid, the gid, the home directory, the login shell etc</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting on linux - Essential Commands</title><link>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/linux-troubleshooting-essential-commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/linux-troubleshooting-essential-commands/</guid><description>1. How long this machine is running from? ❯ uptime 16:35:57 up 10 days, 1:01, 1 user, load average: 0.00, 0.01, 0.05 The output shows the current time, how long the system has been running (up 10 days), the number of logged-in users, and the system load averages over the last 1, 5, and 15 minutes. Low load averages like these indicate an idle system.
2. Whoami (who am i) This command prints the effective userid of the current user.</description></item><item><title>Securely passing AWS IAM credentials to pods running in any Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/pods-aws-credentials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sretreats.github.io/post/published/pods-aws-credentials/</guid><description>Securely passing AWS IAM credentials to pods running in any Kubernetes cluster
to create an https://docs.aws.amazon.com/eks/latest/userguide/connector_IAM_role.html
First we need to create an IAM role for your cluster
Register a cluster in EKS with custom name and select the role created above.
It ask you to download a yaml file (It will ask you only once so be sure to download that yaml file without reloading the page.)
Apply the yaml an it will bring up a pod</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sretreats.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sretreats.github.io/about/</guid><description>Welcome to SRE Treats – your go-to space for learning, exploring, and mastering the world of Site Reliability Engineering (SRE).
This site is dedicated to sharing practical insights, proven techniques, and real-world experiences from working as an SRE. Whether you’re new to reliability engineering or an experienced engineer looking to sharpen your skills, SRE Treats is designed to provide valuable resources and knowledge that help you build, operate, and scale reliable systems.</description></item></channel></rss>